Willowbrook Review Panel; Records apap127
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Compliance [RESTRICTED], 1975-1980; 4; 16.0 cubic ft.
  - Related Facilities Compliance [RESTRICTED], 1975-1980; 4.2; 4.4 cubic ft.
    - Compliance Reports, Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1979 (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Compliance Reports, Manhattan Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Compliance Reports, Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1976 August (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Compliance Reports, Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1976 July (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Compliance Reports, Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1977 March (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Compliance Reports, Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1978 September (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Compliance Reports, Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1979 September (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Operational Plan, Automated Status Reports [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 19)
    - Operational Plan, Automated Status Reports [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 20)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Corona Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 September (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 21)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Corona Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 22)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Corona Unit [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 23)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Corona Unit [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 1 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 24)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Glen Oaks Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Glen Oaks Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Glen Oaks Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Glen Oaks Unit [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Howard Park Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Howard Park Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Howard Park Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Operational Plan, Bernard Fineson Developmental Center-Howard Park Unit [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain I [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 9)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain I [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 10)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain I [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 11)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain I [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain II-IV [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain II-IV [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain II-IV [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Operational Plan, Bronx Developmental Center-Domain II-IV [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Operational Plan, Brooklyn Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Operational Plan, Brooklyn Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Operational Plan, Brooklyn Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 19)
    - Operational Plan, Brooklyn Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Operational Plan, Kings Park Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Operational Plan, Kings Park Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Gouverneur Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Gouverneur Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Gouverneur Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Keener Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Keener Unit [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 9)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Sheridan Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 10)
    - Operational Plan, Manhattan Developmental Center-Sheridan Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 11)
    - Operational Plan, Report on Validation of Willowbrook-Related Facilities [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1977; Undated (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1977; Undated (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 3 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 19)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center-Domain III [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center-Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1978-1979 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center-Kings Park Unit Phase-Out [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 9)
    - Operational Plan, Wassaic Developmental Center-Wingdale Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 10)
    - Operational Plan, Wassaic Developmental Center-Wingdale Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 11)
    - Operational Plan, Wassaic Developmental Center-Wingdale Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Operational Plan, Wassaic Developmental Center-Wingdale Unit [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center-Domain I [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 4 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Operational Plan, Suffolk Developmental Center [RESTRICTED], Undated (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center-Domain II [RESTRICTED], 1975-1976 (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center-Domain III and IV [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center-Domain II [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Operational Plan, Westchester Developmental Center-Domain II [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Staffing Compliance [RESTRICTED], 1978-1980 (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Staffing Compliance [RESTRICTED], 1978-1980 (Box 5 (4-Compliance [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
- Community Placement [RESTRICTED], 1974-1981; 5; 19.8 cubic ft.
  This series consists of material related to the process of placing Willowbrook class members in group homes or family care situations, as mandated by the terms of the 1975 Consent Decree. The series is restricted because it contains information about specific named residents of Willowbrook and other developmental centers.
  - Metropolitan Placement Unit Files [RESTRICTED], 1976-1981; 5.1; 3.2 cubic ft.
    The Metropolitan Placement Unit was a New York State agency created to develop community residences for Willowbrook class members. This subseries consists of the Willowbrook Review Panel's files related to the MPU. It includes reports on MPU activities, correspondence from MPU director Barbara Blum, reports on the development of community residences, and other related files.
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Bronx Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Brooklyn Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Data Sheets, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Data Sheets, Brooklyn [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Data Sheets, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Data Sheets, Queens [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Data Sheets, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Data Sheets, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Long Island Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 9)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Manhattan Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 10)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Queens Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 11)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Staten Island Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Upstate Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Report [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, April 1976, Report [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, Report Appendices [RESTRICTED], 1976 April (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Brooklyn [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 19)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Queens [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 20)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 21)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Drafts [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 22)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Extra Materials, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 23)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Extra Materials, Brooklyn [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 24)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Extra Materials, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 25)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Extra Materials Queens [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 26)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, Extra Materials, State Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 27)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Data Sheet, First Typed Draft [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 28)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Initial Summary [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 29)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Sample, Bronx Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 30)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Sample Brooklyn Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 31)
    - Community Placement Plan Audit, October 1976, Sample, Long Island, Kings Park, Suffolk Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 1 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 32)
    - Community Placement Audit, October 1976, Sample Manhattan Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Community Placement Audit, October 1976, Sample Queens Placement [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Community Placement Audit, October 1976, Sample Staten Island Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Community Placement Audit, October 1976, Sample Upstate Placements [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Community Placement Audit, October 1976, Summary and Comparison Information [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Community Placement Audit, October 1976, October 1976, Summary Matrices [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Community Placement Audit, Appendices [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Community Placement Audit, Debriefing Drafts [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
    - Community Placement Audit, Drafts [RESTRICTED], 1976; Undated (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 9)
    - Community Placement Audit, Miscellaneous [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 10)
    - Community Placement Audit, Training Materials [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 11)
    - Community Placement Audit, April 1976-October 1976, Debriefing [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Community Placement Audit, Report [RESTRICTED], 1977 April (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Background Information [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Data Sheets, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Data Sheets, Queens [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Data Sheets, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Data Sheets, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Data Sheets, Brooklyn [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 19)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Final Draft [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 20)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, First Typed Draft [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 21)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Report Draft [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 22)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Forms and Directions [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 23)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Summary Matrices [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 24)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1977, Telephone Verifications, Data Sheets [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 25)
    - Community Placement Audit, July 1977, Debriefing [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 26)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Data Compilation, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 27)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Data Compilation, Brooklyn, 1977 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 28)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Data Compilation, Manhattan, 1977 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 29)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Data Compilation, Queens [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 30)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Data Compilation, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 2 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 31)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Data Summary [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 1)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, First typed Draft [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 2)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Post-Audit Materials [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 3)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1977, Telephone Verification [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 4)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1978, Audit Materials [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 5)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1978, Preparations [RESTRICTED], 1977-1978 (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 6)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1978, Correspondence [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 7)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1978, Data Compilation [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 8)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1978, Pre-Audit Materials [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 9)
    - Community Placement Audit, May 1978, Telephone Verification [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 10)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 11)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Bronx [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 12)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Brooklyn [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 13)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Broome County [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 14)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Broome County [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 15)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 16)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 17)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Manhattan [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 18)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Queens Developmental Center, Bernard Fineson Memorial School [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 19)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 20)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Staten Island [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 21)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Suffolk [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 22)
    - Community Placement Audit, November 1978, Wassaic and Westchester [RESTRICTED] (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 23)
    - Community Placement Audit, Data Compilation, All Borough Developmental Services Offices [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 3 (5-Community Placement [RESTRICTED]), Folder 24)
  - Community Placement Audit Files [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978; 5.2; 3.6 cubic ft.
    The Review Panel closely monitored the placement of Willowbrook residents in the community and was quick to designate placements as invalid if they did not comply exactly with the terms of the consent Decree. Since it was not feasible for the Panel to review every placement in detail, a series of community placement audits were conducted. Trained auditors examined the records of a sample of all residents placed in a designated time frame, spoke with both the client and the primary care provider, and analyzed the suitability of the client's daily schedule of programming. This subseries contains the raw data from each of these audits including worksheets used by auditors to evaluate each placement, notes from interviews and site visits, and copies of class member records and placement plans. Also included are summaries of audit data and final reports on findings.